Emotion is a complex psychological state that involves three distinct components: a subjective experience, a physiological response, and a behavioral or expressive response.
Greeting is an act of communication in which human beings intentionally make their presence known to each other, to show attention to, and to suggest a type of relationship (usually cordial) or social status.
Love is a range of strong and positive emotional and mental states, from the most sublime virtue or good habit, the deepest interpersonal affection, to the simplest pleasure.
Sadness is an emotional pain associated with, or characterized by, feelings of disadvantage, loss, despair, grief, helplessness, disappointment and sorrow.
Happiness is an emotional state characterized by feelings of joy, satisfaction, contentment, and fulfillment. While happiness has many different definitions, it is often described as involving positive emotions and life satisfaction.
Anger is an intense emotional state involving a strong uncomfortable and non-cooperative response to a perceived provocation, hurt or threat.
Fear is an emotion induced by perceived danger or threat, which causes physiological changes and ultimately behavioral shifts, such as fleeing, hiding, or freezing from perceived traumatic events.
Surprise is a brief mental and physiological state, a startle response experienced by animals and humans as the result of an unexpected event.
Disgust is an emotional response of rejection or revulsion to something potentially contagious or something considered offensive, distasteful, or unpleasant.
Trust is a firm belief in the reliability, truth, ability, or strength of someone or something.
Anticipation is an emotion involving pleasure or anxiety in considering or awaiting an expected event.
Joy is a feeling of great pleasure and happiness.
Sorrow is a feeling of deep distress caused by loss, disappointment, or other misfortune suffered by oneself or others.
Hope is an optimistic state of mind that is based on an expectation of positive outcomes with respect to events and circumstances in one's life or the world at large.
Despair is the complete loss or absence of hope.
Guilt is a cognitive or an emotional experience that occurs when a person believes or realizes—accurately or not—that they have compromised their own standards of conduct or have violated universal moral standards and bear significant responsibility for that violation.
Pride is an emotional state deriving from a person's sense of their own dignity or value or those of something or someone close to them.
Shame is a painful feeling of humiliation or distress caused by the consciousness of wrong or foolish behavior.
Love is the only force capable of transforming an enemy into a friend.
Kindness is the language which the deaf can hear and the blind can see.
